Guide to the Philip Whalen Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Poems and Manuscripts,1941-1971
  - At the Launderette, 1965 September 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - At the place of the bearded hemlock ..., circa 1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Autobiographical Notice (for Don Allen's anthology), 1964 July 15 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - B.C., 1961 October 7 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Babel Revisited, 1951 November 16 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - A Ballad, With Notes, 1941 February 11 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bath After Work, 1951 July 29 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Be ruled by beauty & her willfulness ..., 1958 August 28 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Because I can love out ..., 1955 November 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Because I don't believe any airplane can kill a Swede ..., 1961 May 9 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Being here at the last American edge ..., 1958 July 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Belle poete de la nuit ... 1957 February 4 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - A bending, a turning ..., 1962 August 20 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Beyond what figure ..., 1963 September 20 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bitter melons ... 1958 July 16 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Black iron trees ... (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The blank wall ... (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bleakness Farewell, 1965 January 26 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bolero, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - A Botanickal Phrenzy, 1964 January 18 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Braincandy (misc. pages, etc.),1952-1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Broke it ..., 1960 February 16 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Brueghel: "The Fall of Icarus," 1963 September 20 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - But I know what I like ..., 1951 December 29 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - California is Odious but Indispensable, 1965 May 7 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Card #21 Le Monde, 1965 May 24 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Carolinian (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Champ Chair Modern Jazz Coffee, 1966 October 6 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Chariot for Jess Collins, 1962 March 30 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Cheerful Thought on Thinking on the Old Addage of Crime Doesn't Pay (Well), 1941 February 27 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Choose momentary anguish ... (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chi-chen-itzh, '41, 1941 March 25 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Clambake, 1941 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Clean Song, 1964 February 18 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Coat Pocket Poem, 1965 April 8 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - A Colorful Poem for Aram ..., 1967 February 4 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Confirmation (for L.J.R.), 1948 February 8 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The consequences (not in any punitive sense) ..., 1960 January 6 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Continue ..., 1952 June 22 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Coordinates, 1963 January 24 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Corinthian Columns, 1964 March 22 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Corvallis Down the Road, 1958 May 18 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - A Country Without Ruins (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Crowded, 1966 June 12 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - A cup of tea ..., 1962 November 5 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Daily Bread, 1963 April 21 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Daydream, 1961 June 27 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dear Bloch, 1957 December 7 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dear Mr. President, 1964 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dear Young Contemporaries, 1959 August 25 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Death is coming through ..., 1942 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Death of Boston, 1960 October 23 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Demachi, 1966 November 25 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Denunciation: or, Unfrock'd Again, 1956 March 11 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Desert Tortoise, 1954 April 6 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Dharma Youth League, 1966 December 28 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Diamond Noodle (Box 10, Folder 8 to 11)
  - A difficult day ..., 1953 January 4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - A Dim View of Berkeley in the Spring, 1957 April 23 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Disgust with an Poetickal Evening at Miss Q's House, 1965 March 29 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Divisadero St., 1964 April 18 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Double Take, 1963 November 17 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Doukhobor Proverb: for Osfear Heiserman, 1965 March 24 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dream, 1941 March 6 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dream, 1960 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dream & Excursus, Arlington, Mass., 1960 October 14 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dried upstanding grasses…, 1963 March 11 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Driver Lost at Coos Bay, 1957 December 7 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Duerden Says: "Life is therapy," 1961 April 30 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dust, feathers, &c on the flloor ..., 1960 February 4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - EAMD, 1963 March 9 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Early Autumn in Upper Noe Valley (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Earth Here Bears Only Mountains, 1948 January 13 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Easy Living, 1961 October 7 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - L'education classique (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Education Continues Along; for Clark Coolidge, 1965 August 27 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Eikei Soji, 1966 May 10 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - An Elegy Upon the Untimely death of Mrs. W — F, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The end of a day ..., 1959 May 27 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - End of Life, 1942 May 18 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - L'enfant prodigue, 1965 August 3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Engineer, 1951 1956 June 24 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Envoi: Sauk Mountain, 1953 1953 November 15 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - [Epigram], 1963 July 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - An Epigram, 1964 April 28 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Epithalamion Made in Holy Week for the Marriage of NDC to HCP, 1948 March 29 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Epithalamium, for Mertis & Brian, 1959 May 23 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Esprit d'escalier rant, directed at Dr. T. Parkinson's class…, 1957 January 9 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Essex was a Cowboy in Vermont, 1960 May 28 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Europa (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Evening in the Jungle, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Everything I ever loved ..., 1961 February 8 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Explanation to M.A., 1962 October 21 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Fantasia V (Liebesffeud), 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fantasia XVIII, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Farewell!, 1959 October 10 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Farewell to the Appendix, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Feather Truth Weighs 10,000 Pounds, 1965 July 12 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fell Street, 1964 September 8 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fifteen Impressions by Philidor Fhinch, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fillmore Hob Nob Carburetor, 1962 October 15 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fire depends on the arrangement of the fuel…, 1957 December 30 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The First Day is the Longest, 1952 June 22 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The First Day of November, 1956 November 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The first I ever saw of you ..., 1966 August 29 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The First of August, 1965 August 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The First of November 1958 1958 November 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The first step of the pyramid is Apocalypse …, 1964 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Flexible Mind, 1966 May 20 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fog-horns, 1959 October 9 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Fond Farewell to The Chicago Review 1958 June 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Fond Literary Talk, 1958 July 20 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For Albert Saijo, 1960 December 18 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For a Picture by Mike-Nathan, 1959 April 4 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For Brother Antoninus, 1963 March 28 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For C., 1957 April 20 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For Diane Super (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For Irving Rosenthal, 1960 July 20 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For Jack Spicer, 1962 April 23 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For K. W., Senex, 1955 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For Miss Margaret Brown, 1964 August 25 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For My Father, 1953 January 3 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - For one portion of a day ..., 1951 November 16 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - For Valentine's Day, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 45 Years Since the Fall of the Ch'ing Dynasty, 1957 October 10 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Four Ormolu Pieces; for Stanly Moore (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Fourth of October, 1963 1963 October 4 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fragment of a Letter, Unsent, 1965 April 4 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fragment of Great Beauty & Stillness, 1965 February 22 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fragments of a Day in Summer, [1941] (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Friday already half- ..., 1963 June 28 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Friendship Greetings, 1961 September 23 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - From an Envelope Addressed to Charles Olson, 1958 July 3 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - From deep in the forest ... (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - From the annals, of the Adelaide Crapsey-Oswald Spengler…, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - A Further Emblem, 1960 February 6 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Further Notice, 1956 September 22 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Gallery, Mill Valley, 1962 December 11 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Garden, 1965 October 24 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Genetics, 1965 August 5 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Geological Note, 1948 August (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Giant Sequoias, 1965 July 28 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Ginkakuji Michi, 1966 May 10 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Golden Gate Park, 1963 August 25 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - A good beginning here- ... (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Good News and Gospel, 1965 August 12 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Gradus ad Parnassum, 1963 October 8 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Grand Design, 1966 October 27 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Grand historical ode ..., 1965 March 19 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Grand monster hymn to St. Euglena ..., 1958 July 3 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Grandmother,1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Great Beyond Denver, 1964 January 18 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Great Heidelberg Tun, 1965 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Great Instauration (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Green plums ..., 1963 June 8 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Greeks, 1965 August 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Groundhog Day, 1965 1965 January 31 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Haiku, for Gary Snyder, 1965 January 15 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Harrangue from Newport, to John Wieners, 1957 September 21 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hart Crane, 1948 February 24 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Having had everything ..., 1955 October 22 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Having no place in this world ..., 1959 April 2 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hebrew Variations (in memoriam E. B.), 1956 September 26 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Heigh-ho, Nobody's at Home, 1962 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hekate, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hello to All the Folks Back Home, 1962 December 13 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Higher Criticism, 1965 August 6 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Historical Disquisitions, 1960 July 11 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Homage to Dante, 1965 September 4 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Homage to Lucretius, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Homage to Robert Creeley, 1956 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Homage to Rodin, 1961 March 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Homage to W.B.Y., 1963 November 23 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Homage to William Seward Burroughs, 1965 February 20 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Honeymoon, 1965 August 24 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Horror Tales, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hour Before Dawn, 1941 February 20 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - How Beautiful, 1963 April 11 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - How many red leaves are green ..., 1963 May 25 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - How to forget about going to town ..., 1962 November 5 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - How Was Your Trip to L.A.?, 1963 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - How We Live the More Abundant Life in America, 1963 February 18 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hymn to One Afraid, 1941 March 12 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - I am a coward… 1963 June 16 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I am King Giant Dragon Sun, 1959 May 8 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I am outside, outside …, 1956 July 30 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I am writing so that you will know ..., 1941 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I don't know ..., 1958 September 29 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I dreamed you we're mad at me ..., 1962 March 30 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I Give Up, 1956 September 22 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I know what I love …, 1957 March 28 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I learned in college ... 1956 August 28 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I like to think that when we're old ... (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I look at the window sill ..., 1963 July 8 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I pretend nobody knows who I am ..., 1960 January 15 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I sit listening to my pretty teeth decay … (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I Think of Mountains, 1958 October 28 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I walk along whistling a piece of Rachmaninoff ..., 1960 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I walk to the end of this street ..., 1958 July 20 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I want to be at home ..., 1963 September 4 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I - who care nothing except for beauty …, 1963 March 31 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - I wrote letters & left the house ..., 1956 October 23 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Idol, 1962 February 12 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ignorantaccio, 1961 July 7 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Illness, 1963 October 5 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - I'm concerned about you ..., 1960 September 26 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - I'm going back in the fall ..., 1942 August 24 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - I'm not in the mood ..., 1941 February 17 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Imaginary Speeches for a Brazen Head 1966-1967
    - Drafts (Box 12)
    - Notebook,1966-1967 (Box 12)
    - Notebook, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Notebook, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Typescript, (2 Folders) (Box 12)
    - Typescript- Final Version (Box 12)
  - Imagination of the Taj Mahal, 1965 May 7 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Imitation of Something Classical, 1956 August 4 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Impatient with the beauty of this day ..., 1958 November 25 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - In California, 1952 May-1954 February (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - In Memory of a Statesman, 1957 December 27 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - In one of the less expensive suburbs of my brain ..., 1958 July 26 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - In the Middle of the Night (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - In the midst of a black eternity ..., 1942 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - In white light storefront living room ..., 1960 November 20 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - India Print, March, 1964 November 17 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The India Print Bedspread, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Inside Stuff, 1963 October 15 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Invitation, 1941 February 27 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Invocation & Dark Sayings, in the Tibetan Style, 1956 August 10 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Invocation & Theophany, 1964 April 14 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Invocation: to the Muse, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - An Irregular Ode, 1960 January 3 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Israeli Woman Told Me (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - It is the season of love ..., 1959 January 9 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Itchy, 1960 April 15 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - I've had it hot ..., 1958 July 26 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - I've sacrificed my parents ..., 1965 May 12 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Japanese Tea Garden Golden Gate Park in Spring, 1965 April 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Jour de Schmoo (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Judgment, 1966 May 23 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Kindness of Strangers: Poems,1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Labor Day, 1965 September 6 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Landscape, 1941 March 7 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Landsend, 1960 July 20 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Language and Writing, July, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Large remember'd moments ... 1965 February 28 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Last Day of 1957 1957 December 30 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Last Part of an Illustrated Children's Book in a Fever Dream, 1963 December 16 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Late Afternoon, 1964 August 27 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The leaves rustling .., 1942 July 27 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lemon Trees, 1965 October 24 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Let us now praise ... (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Letter to ACH, 1942 January 16 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Letter, to Mme E.T.S., 1958 January 2 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Letter, to Michael McClure, 11: iii: 63, 1963 March 11 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lewis River Bath, 1951 July 29 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Libra, an Emblem, of the Scales or Balance, 1960 February 6 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Life and Art, 1961 June 22 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Life and Death and a Letter to My Mother Beyond them Both, 1963 May 14 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Life of Literature, 1965 July 17 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Like a bird ..., 1966 December 8 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Lines to a Thwarted Tiger (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Literary life in the golden west ..., 1957 May 20 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Little black dots ..., 1963 July 12 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Live Oregon, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Loitering in the kitchen…, 1961 May 8 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Lost Poem, 1964 March (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Love Love Love Again, 1965 April 7 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - M for Robert Duncan, 1965 July 13 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Madrigal, 1965 March 15 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Mahayana, 1965 April 5 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Martyrdom of St. Sebastian (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Martyrdom of Two Pagans, 1955 March 24 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Maurine Penstemon, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Max! (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Maya Morning, 1941 March 6 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Measure, 1959 September 8 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Meditation: in October I'll be Thirty-Three, 1956 August 21 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Mélisande, 1941 March 13 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Memorial to the Throne (for J.K.), 1955 September 29 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Merry Meet; Merry Part, 1964 March 27 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Message Before Aram Awakes, 1965 April 30 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Meta, [1951] (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Mid Marble Cold New Table, 1960 February 24 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mid-morning in Our Century (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mill Valley, 1962 October 27 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mill Valley, 1963 March 4 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mill Valley Night Raccoons, 1962 March 17 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Minor Moralia, 1959 August 21-1962 October 27 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Miraculous Riches,1958-1959 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Miserably Drunk at Coit Tower, 1953 February 4 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Missa Solemnis, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mr. Patterson has Gone Away to Rest and Write (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - A Morning Walk, 1965 April 21 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Monday, in the Evening, 1961 August 21 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Monday was a glorious day…, 1963 February 19 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The moon she is a busy whore … (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Morning in the Jungle, 1941 February 19 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Motion Day, 1959 January 25 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Movie Night, 1960 May 29 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The muse is flown ..., 1942 July 27 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - My only home is love ..., 1956 September 23 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - My Shakespeare, Rise!, &c., 1961 August 21 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - My songs Induce Prophetic Dreams (Poems), 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mysteries of 1961 1963 September 14 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Mystery of Prometheus, 1959 March 11 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The Mystery of the Alphabet, 1965 August 3 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Mystery Poem, for a Birthday Present, 1963 October 2 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Native Folk Speech,1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Natural Curiosities at Gilliam & Bisbee's, 1954 January 28 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The nexus of being ..., 1948 January 12 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Newport North-window View (for Bruce McGaw), 1958 July 27 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - A New Voyage, 1952 December 28 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - New York City, 1959 November 9 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Night and Morning Michaelangelo, 1963 March 1 and 1965 July 14 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1935, 1965 June 15 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - No crevasses that you can't jump across ..., 1962 February 12 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - No one is ever two ..., 1955 October 20 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - No right ..., 1951 July 22 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Not an Answer, 1952 March 23 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Note on the "Concerto in F," [1943] (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - November First,1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Now I keep reaching outwards…, 1963 September 12 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Now I see ray part in the story…, 1964 November 3 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Now you're out of the country …, 1960 March 24 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Ode (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ode to Chow Mein, 1941 February 21 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ode to My Memory, 1941 March 10 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ode to the Officers, 1941 February 18 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ode to the Porcupine, 1942 April 13 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ode to the Voice of Experience, 1941 March 3 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "0f course," She Said (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Oh Henrietta! …, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Oh Yes. Vancouver, 1963 August (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - On a lady's Hat…, 1941 February 28 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - On the Campus, 1956 July 30 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - On the Death of Ross Lockridge Jr. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - One day you wore a different perfume. ..., 1960 January 28 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - The one is reduced .., 1958 February 22 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - One of My Favorite Songs is "Stormy weather," 1961 September 20 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - One Page Poem, 1963 June 27 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - The Ones that Mean it and the Ones that Lie, 1956 June 24 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Opening Rainy-season Sesshin, 1966 May 1 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Opening the Mountain, Tamalpais, 1965 October 22 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Optimist's Spring, 1948 March 24 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Order Out of Chaos, 1965 August 18 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Orders, 1958 May 13 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - The Oregon Country ..., 1941 January 15 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Orlovsky, Upon the Fair Sex, 1959 June 5 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Out of it, 1953 April 8 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Over First St. Clear ..., 1956 December 13 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Owed to a Loan Shark, 1941 March 27 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - On Bear's Head, 1950-1968
    - Content's list (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Page Proofs (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Title Page Mock-up (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Proofs (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Palace Café, 1960 March 8 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Palimpsest, 1965 August 25 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Panda, 1942 April 4 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Papyrus Catalogue, 1964 January 13 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Paranoia Revisited, 1965 August 16 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Paranoia Takes, 1960 November 24 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Part of a Lesson, 1952 June 18 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The past around us is less than golden ... (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - "A Penny for the Old Guy" for Aram Saroyan, 1965 March 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Pentecost (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Perfection Breakfast, 1962 August 19 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Persephone, 1951 September 16 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Philippic, Against Whitehead & a Friend, 1961 October 8 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - PW His Recantation, 1963 May 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Picture of a Mind, 1959 October 23 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Plaster Muse: 6 Poems in the Classic Mode (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Plaster of Paris; Helen of Troy, 1965 October 18 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - A Platonic Variation, 1966 June 23 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - A Pleasant Sexy Feeling ..., 1962 February 12 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Please Pay Attention, 1959 August 13 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Plumtree Moonlight Crocodile Soap ..., 1958 March 22 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Plums, Metaphysics, an Investigation ..., 1963 June 17 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - La plus ca chance ..., 1955 February 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Poets and Prophets on My Floor, 1956 October 5 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Point Richmond, 1966 February 13 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Poor, 1961 October 7 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Pop Doughnut,, 1965 July 2 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Portland in the Evening, 1965 December 8 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Portland revisited ..., 1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Portland Unvisited; Four Satires (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Powerless! ..., 1959 July 14 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Prelude & Fantasia in 3 flats (I), 1943 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Priapic Hymn, 1965 March 22 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Problem, 1964 April 13 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Professor, 1963 January 6 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Promise, 1965 August 9 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Prophecy, 1962 July 16 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Prose Takeout, Portland, 1958 September 13 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Quite alone ... (Box 15, Folder 5)